Hello.
In this next lecture, I'm going to go over how to add sound and sound effects to our game to get started.
If we right click and create a new folder and call this sounds.
Head inside here.
And then briefly close on our engine attached.
In this lecture, I'm going to make sure to include all these sound files, drag and move them into
Unreal Engine.
We're now ready to set up our sounds.
So we're in level one.
So in level one, I'm going to make it play this background music.
In order to do that, we can go here and go open up a blueprint, right click and go event picking,
play and event being in play.
We're going to play sound to DH.
And for the sound so that the end game music and go compile and save.
And now if I play level one, it should play that pattern.
So when I was in level one, it played that music.
If you have your own music, you could simply just replace this with your own song.
And now on that level, you play the sound.
Right now.
If I let that song play through, it would only play the song once.
If you want music to loop inside of your game, head inside that sound and just make sure you check
this looping box.
And when the song ends, it will just play it again.
We can just save this and close this.
The next thing I'm going to go over is how to add some sound effects.
We can make the game play a certain sound effect whenever we pick up a coin.
You may have noticed I have for coin sound effects.
What we can do is make it randomly play one of those sounds where my player character picks up a coin.
In order to do that.
We can right click and go sound and select sound cue.
Just call this my random coin.
If we open it up and then just briefly close this tab.
And if we just select these four sounds.
And drag them in here.
And it's going to say we play a coin.
One, two, three and four.
If I just drag off one of these outputs and look for random and just add three more inputs and connect
all these nodes.
I'll then connect the output to here.
And now if I go play Q it's going to pick one of these random sounds to play.
I'm just going to click this again.
And this time it played way Player Coin three.
So we can just use this if we have loads of sounds and you want to play one random sound effect.
Let's implement this into our coins.
So if I close this and slap my coin blueprint.
Whenever my player character overlaps it and picks it up, I am just going to move all these notes back.
And we are just going to drag up here and look for play sound at location.
The sound we're going to play is going to be the random coin that we just made and where we're going
to play it.
We can just right click and get actor location and connect this here.
I'll compile and save this.
And if I close this.
I'm just going to remove the music from playing and now I'm going to play.
And my player picks up a coin.
Play one of those sound effects.
I want to go over one last way that we can add sound effects to our game, and that is using the paper
Z and a notify system.
So we have this sword sound effect.
If I go over to my player card folder and to the animation folder.
And if I go over to the animation source, select the attack animation.
If we just go track and go at new notify track and go to around frame four, we can right click and
go add, notify and step play sound.
If I select the sound here, I can go to the details panel and set the sound that I want to play at
this specific frame.
And I'm going to select my sort sound.
So now, if I was to go play, when it reaches that frame in the animation, I'll play the small sound.
So let's pause this, save this, close this, and then go play.
And if I attack.
When I reached that specific plea to notify, he'll play the sound that I've assigned there.
So that's how you can add some sound effects to your game.